SERGEI KOZLOV

System Administrator

- S sergeykozlov.ru

 hello@sergeykozlov.ru

 https://www.linkedin.com/in/sergeykozlovru/
- 🕒 +79109087360 🔞 Smiryagina street, Novomichurinsk, Ryazan, Russia. 🛗 12/1981

SUMMARY

System administrator with over 20 years of experience. Successfully manages the IT environment of a large company in the energy sector. Responsibly ensures the operation of Bare-metal servers and any complex cloud technologies, 4 Internet providers, 130+ users using dozens corporate services. Is helping to grow the annual revenue of the corporation. Delivering 15% IT budget savings.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

System Administrator

2013-present

☐ 'GEH TER' (branch), Novomichurinsk, Russia Maintenance of large power plants

- Implemented an automated system that daily ensures the safety and protection of access to corporate data and user documents. Tiered Backup Strategy protects 9TB of corporate data.
- Analyzed 100+ corporate security issues. Successfully applied modern protected tools and protocols for safety user access and payment transactions.
- Implemented an electronic document management system (EDMS) for 70 users that reduced the time spent on routine tasks by 75%, acknowledged by management for being proactive.
- Connected 4 Internet sources to the local network of the enterprise. This made it possible to eliminate interruptions in the operation of corporate services (0 failures in the Internet over the past 9 years).
- Designed, configured, maintained and connected 7 remote offices to the corporate network, using new hybrid types of communication, including LAN, WAN, VPN, and wireless networks. This increased speed by 16 times and reduced denial of service from 18 hours a month to 0.

System Administrator

2000-2013

☐ 'Teploenergoremont', Novomichurinsk, Russia Maintenance of large power plants

- Managed 8 servers providing remote access, storage of 3 TB of data, execution of 7+ user services for 115 corporate users.
- Successfully applied Active Directory and Linux/Unix user access policies, which allowed and prevented unauthorized access and data leakage.

EDUCATION

College of Electronics

2002-2006

Associate's degree in Computer Sciences (diploma with distinction)

Specialization: computer and network technician

All Language skills English – (B2), Czech – (A1), Russian – (C2)

TECHNOLOGICAL SKILLS

Linux Windows Server
 Active Directory
 Networking
 Technical Support
 Virtualization

SOFT SKILLS

■ Time management ■ Communication ■ Problem-solving ■ Teamwork ■ Attention to detail

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

• Over the past 3 years, trained as mentor 7 students as programmers for various industries. All students have success completed studies and got a diploma.